Let the sunshine in!
Hair is a music, drama, comedy film directed by Miloš Forman.
Upon receiving his draft notice and leaving his family ranch in Oklahoma, Claude heads to New
York and befriends a tribe of long-haired hippies on his way to boot camp.
Claude Hooper Bukowski, played by John Savage.
George Berger, played by Treat Williams.
Sheila Franklin, played by Beverly D'Angelo.
Jeannie Ryan, played by Annie Golden.
Lafayette aka Hud, played by Dorsey Wright.
Woof, played by Don Dacus.
Hair is a 1979 musical anti-war comedy-drama film directed by Miloš Forman and adapted for the screen by
Michael Weller, based on the 1968 Broadway musical Hair: The American Tribal Love-Rock Musical.
Set against the backdrop of the hippie counterculture of the Vietnam era, the film focuses on a Vietnam War
draftee who meets and befriends a "tribe" of hippies while en route to the army induction center.
The hippies and their leader introduce him to marijuana, LSD, and their
environment of unorthodox relationships and draft evasion.
The film stars an ensemble cast including John Savage, Treat Williams, Beverly D'Angelo,
Annie Golden, Dorsey Wright, Don Dacus, Cheryl Barnes and Ronnie Dyson.
Dance scenes were choreographed by Twyla Tharp and
were performed by Tharp's dancers.
Hair was nominated for two Golden Globes: Best Motion Picture – Musical or
Comedy, and New Star of the Year in a Motion Picture (for Williams).
The film explores themes of vietnam war, new york city, army, hippie, free love.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.